Quentin Blacklock

blacklockq@gmail.com

Software Development, Data Analytics, Strategic Management of Technology, People & Knowledge

I have a strong manufacturing background with 20 + years of experience that includes operations, technology and management, that has prepared me for the challenges as business seeks digitally transformation.

I seek new opportunities to solve business problems through software development, data analytics, and the strategic management of technology, people and knowledge.

Passionate about lifelong learning, I am currently exploring gamification in business, Power BI, and social knowledge management.

Outside of geek stuff, Quentin enjoys golfing, distance cycling.

Experience

Chief Information Officer Times Printing LLC May 2016 - Present

- Leading end to end technology transition post acquisition.
- Developed New Reporting Systems for Job Cost Analysis, Manufacturing Performance Reporting.
- Developed New Sales Compensation Plan Automation.
- Planning technological integration into the new parent company.
- Planning data center and infrastructure updates.
- Leader of Compliance Team for FSC & SFI Certifications.
- IT Manager.
- Administration and Support of Enterprise Business Applications.
- General Systems and Network Administration of over 200 users in an enterprise environment.
- Director of Campus Security.

Chief Information Officer Times Printing Co. Inc. April 2014 May 2016

- Provided data and analytics support to management through due diligence and acquisition.
- Developed Manufacturing Performance Analytics for Equipment and Operators.
- Developed Dashboard Portal for Customer Service.
- Implemented Server-Based Document Scanning and OCR System.
- Developed Management App Date Database for Invoice Scan to Customer Email.
- Leader of cross-functional Future Business Systems Research Team.
- Leader of Compliance Team for FSC & SFI Certifications.
- Developed Internal Audit software for FSC & SFI Compliance.
- IT Manager.
- Administration and Support of Enterprise Business Applications.
- General Systems and Network Administration of over 200 users in an enterprise environment.

Systems & Software Engineer Times Printing Co. Inc. October 2011 - April 2014

- 75% Software Engineer 25% IT & Industrial Systems Engineer.
- Implemented Document Management System and Wireless Mobile Units.
- Developed UPS & Fedex Integration to Accounting with Reporting.
- Developed CRM App for Billing.
- Web Enabled Legacy Scheduling System.
- Developed Customer Growl Implementation for Schedule Change Notification.
- Developed Advanced Job Cost Analysis Tools.
- Developed Slow Moving Paper Inventory Analysis Tools.
- Line of Business Application Development.
- Project Manager Fiber Internet and PRI Installation.
- Project Manager New Phone System Installation.
- Industrial Systems Administration and Maintenance over 40 Industrial Computers
- Administration and Support of Enterprise Business Applications.
- General Systems and Network Administration of over 250 users in an enterprise environment.

Programmer Analyst Times Printing Co. Inc. April 2006 - October 2011

- Implemented Warehouse Management System with Barcoding.
- Developed Data Pump between ERP System and Warehouse System.
- Developed Business Specific Administration Module for Warehouse System.
- Developed Replacement Output Module for Warehouse System.
- Developed Bindery Planning Module to ERP System.
- Developed Inventory Search for Warehouse System.
- Line of Business Application Development.
- Microsoft & Crystal Reports.
- Linux System Administration.
- Database Administration.

IT & Finishing Systems Technician Times Printing Co. Inc. February 2004 - April 2006

- Maintained Binding Line Controllers.
- Maintained Industrial Computers.
- Maintained Industrial Ink Jet Printers.
- Developed backup and restore application for industrial systems.
- Modified DOS based Machine Controllers to work with TCPIP. Saved the company \$400,000.

Education

Master of Science Engineering Management Milwaukee School of Engineering - 2014

- GPA 3.96
- Strategic Management of Technology, People and Knowledge.
- Thesis topic: Key Factors for Social Knowledge Management Initiatives.

Masters Certificate Knowledge Management Milwaukee School of Engineering - 2013

- GPA 4.0
- Knowledge Management is the process of capturing, developing, sharing, and effectively using organizational knowledge.

Bachelor of Science Management Information Systems Milwaukee School of Engineering - 2011

- GPA 3.89
- Application Development Focus.
- Project: Warehouse Management Bar-coding. Sold to company, in production.
- Project: Business Intelligence Dashboards.
- Project: Project Management for Charity Fundraiser.
- Coursework: JAVA, Databases, Project Management, Business Intelligence.

Associate Degree Electrical Power Engineering Lakeshore Technical College - 1986

- GPA 3.96
- DC and AC Electricity.
- Digital Electronics.
- Generators and Motor Control Systems.
- Power Transmission.

Technical

Languages	Tools	Operating Systems
C# .NET	Visual Studio 2013, 2010, 2008	Windows 8.1, 7, XP, 2000, NT4
MS SQL	Linq Pad	Windows Server 2008, 2003, 2000
MySQL	Jekyll	Linux
Java	Net Beans	MSDOS
SSRS	Crystal Reports	VMWare
Telerik Reports	Access	